<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-26T09:07:14+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tom Kingdom</title><entry><title type="html">Is there anybody out there?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/01/01/first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is there anybody out there?" /><published>2016-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/01/01/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/01/01/first-post.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve long profited from and admired the transparency of other designers. A few that come to mind are &lt;a href=&quot;https://frankchimero.com/&quot;&gt;Frank Chimero&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://rsms.me/&quot;&gt;Rasmus Anderson&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://joelcalifa.com&quot;&gt;Joel Califa&lt;/a&gt;. This small website is a first step to do just the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exposing ones own working process and thoughts can be intimidating, but the benefits are many. I know I’ll need reminding of it’s value, so here’s 5 benefits for me (and maybe you) to start off and hopfeully keep me going!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;postimage&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;../../../assets/first-post.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;celebrate-success&quot;&gt;Celebrate success&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presenting projects is good way of celebrating success – something rare in the fast paced world of software. It is important to finish anything we do well, and that includes stepping back and saying “that was good”. Writing up a project is a neat way of doing just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;look-back-and-learn&quot;&gt;Look back and learn&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly not everything we do goes well! But even worse is to neglect learning from past failures. Documenting a project forces oneself to look back and learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;confront-fear&quot;&gt;Confront fear&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working and thinking transparently can be scary. What will others think? Will I look silly? Uncertainty leads to keeping quiet, but being transparent forces oneself to confront those fears. The truth is everyone makes mistakes, yet only by owning up to it can one recieve the critique needed to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;make-friends&quot;&gt;Make friends&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At best, the act of documenting ones own thoughts and work will be of help to others. At the very least it’ll be easier to get to know me: how I think and what I value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;think-clearly&quot;&gt;Think clearly&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m someone who at times has too many interests and ideas rattling around my head. Putting it to paper forces oneself to better understand and clarify a thought. In turn this establishes a habit of clearer communication in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;-ive-been-writing-up-notes-for-a-while-but-have-never-posted-any-of-them-in-order-to-match-my-older-notes-to-the-time-in-which-i-initialy-wrote-them-i-will-backdate-anything-written-before-april-2021-this-post-has-also-been-backdated-so-that-it-sits-at-the-start-of-the-post-list&quot;&gt;* I’ve been writing up notes for a while but have never posted any of them. In order to match my older notes to the time in which I initialy wrote them I will backdate anything written before April 2021. This post has also been backdated so that it sits at the start of the post list.&lt;/h5&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’ve long profited from and admired the transparency of other designers. A few that come to mind are Frank Chimero, Rasmus Anderson and Joel Califa. This small website is a first step to do just the same.</summary></entry></feed>